So
supplements, I'm not a huge supplement
first thing I recommend is a like a
complex B vitamin. I don't have any
specific
um
brand that I promote, but there's some
evidence that androgens can increase
your homocysteine levels, so B12 can
help with that. And B and it's a super
safe and super cheap supplement, so for
me
that's that's one I recommend.
Uh creatine monohydrate
it's effective, you know, maybe even
latest evidence it might even improve
your cognitive function if you use
higher than
5 g a day. I think at 10, maybe even
higher than that. Um that's one of those
things is it going to change your life
if you start taking creatine? No, but
beneficial, effective, I think.
Um another supplement that I recommend
to some patients, particularly because I
have a lot of obese guys, is a
supplement called HMB, hydroxy beta
methylbutyrate.
Um and it's a supplement that
reduces muscle protein breakdown while
they're in a calorie deficit, which they
usually are. So sometimes I'll recommend
that. Maca root extract I'll recommend
because it has proven effects on libido
and sex drive. Sometimes L-carnitine I
will prescribe actually to patients
specifically with metabolic syndrome.
And why? Because there's evidence that
um
L-carnitine can help with the metabolic
what's called metabolic inflexibility.
So when you have the obesity that I'm
talking about, you usually have a
dysfunction in your liver and fat cells.
They develop metabolic inflexibility,
which means they can't efficiently
switch from burning sugar to burning
fatty acids. Also happens in your
testes, by the way. Uh which is a huge
problem because if you can't burn fatty
acids, you can't make testosterone. So
the L-carnitine actually is helps in the
process of
um you know, alleviating the congestion
in mitochondria. That's a very lay
person's way of saying it. And um the
patients that benefit the most I think
are the ones with very high C-reactive
protein levels. So if you search
L-carnitine C-reactive protein metabolic
syndrome, there's a few studies showing
L-carnitine can help with that. Um but
that's as far as supplements go, that's
pretty much it. And everything's cheap.
And I don't sell anything direct any of
those things directly, so
um beyond that, not not many supplements
that I would would recommend. You asked
me about peptides. So there are some
patients that are interested in
peptides, and I do sometimes use
tesamorelin. It's been a while since
I've used it. Um but tesamorelin does
reduce your visceral fat, so
you know, um
and probably faster than testosterone
does.
There's some questions about how durable
the effect of tesamorelin is. Like for
example, if you go off it, do you regain
what you lost? Mhm. Some studies seem to
suggest that, but um yeah, that's as far
as like ancillaries. And then obviously
I use a lot of semaglutide, tirzepatide.
Um I use that like crazy. But that's not
a supplement, that would just be another
drug. Yeah. Cialis we use like a Cialis
is virtually a supplement now. You know,
I live a lot of times in Latin America,
and you can just go buy Cialis over the
counter. So
I if you consider Cialis a supplement,
low-dose Cialis also very
popular. So that that's a 5 mg tadalafil
daily.
Yep.
Very safe.
Beneficial not only just for your erect
Well
let's start with erectile function. It's
very good because even if you have
moderate mild erectile dysfunction, it's
very important not to ignore that
because the penile tissue
again to put things in lay terms, it I'm
going to say it's a muscle, it's not a
muscle, but
if you um
if you just ignore it, it tends to get
worse. So if you don't have strong
erections regularly
and you go that way for a long time, you
know, you can actually worsen the
dysfunction, so I think it's important
to treat early. And uh the other thing
is Cialis has other benefits. There's
ergogenic benefits, meaning it can
increase hyperemia to your skeletal
muscle
while you're working out, so that may
have anabolic benefits. It has
mitochondrial effects, so there's some
evidence that it can that it has certain
anti-aging properties. Um
things like that. So and it's very safe.
Very few people have side effects from
low-dose Cialis, and I mean I don't put
everybody on it, you know, but uh if
they even say they have a minor degree
of ED, I think it's pretty slam dunk,
especially now that it's so cheap, too.
Uh and then HCG we use for fertility
preservation. We didn't talk about that,
but
Mhm. you know, that's another thing
someone asked about. And we we use a lot
of HCG because that helps preserve your
fertility in most cases. I mean, it's
not 100% guaranteed, but the vast
majority of men who start injectable
testosterone, who also take 500 IUs of
HCG every other day
will maintain a
a fertility level of sperm counts. Maybe
even some who use 250 every other day
at the risk of increasing side effects,
of course, but I I guess most men over
40, 45, they don't care so much about
their fertility anymore. They don't care
about their fertility, but you know what
some of them do care about is their
testicular volume. So they don't like
the fact that they get atrophy on the
testosterone, or their put in lay terms,
their balls shrink.
So for those guys, yeah, I'll still give
them HCG like if it's really important
to them.
Um but most people don't care.
You know.
Mhm. Um
you know, we all care about different
things, you know.
Yeah. I always mess with my guy. I mean,
are they really that smaller than they
used to be?
But I, you know, I give my guys a hard
time, so
Yeah, I I don't care about that. I don't
care about my hair that I lost way
before TRT, so yeah. Yeah, yeah, I mean,
that's that's good. I'm fighting a
losing battle, unfortunately, but
it is what it is. I I can't
>> look good. Well, you're one of the guys
that looks You have a good You have a
good face for baldness. I think if I was
bald, I'd look like a
a creature from the black lagoon, but
Yeah.
there are guys that can pull it off
good, so you're one of them, maybe. So
that's good.
Yeah.
Anyway, you'll get used to it.